<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Daniel's World</title><link>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel's World</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Servers, Signals, and Self-Reflection</title><link>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/servers-signals-reflection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/servers-signals-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>A week without a post, which you know means a properly busy week for me. When I&amp;rsquo;m not writing, it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;m up to my neck in projects that seemed like good ideas at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The radio repair saga continues, though with a plot twist. The TS930S I&amp;rsquo;ve been wrestling with turned out to be too far gone to be economically viable to repair - it&amp;rsquo;s found a new home at one of the radio clubs now, so at least it&amp;rsquo;s not cluttering up my bench anymore. But nature abhors a vacuum, apparently, so I&amp;rsquo;ve started on a new radio repair project: an old Icom HF transceiver that&amp;rsquo;s got me properly puzzled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frequencies, Fixes, and Phone Calls</title><link>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/frequency-fixes-phone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/frequency-fixes-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sorry this one&amp;rsquo;s a bit late - didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything properly finished by last Sunday, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather post something worth reading than rush out half-thoughts just to meet an arbitrary schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week&amp;rsquo;s been dominated by radio projects, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t surprise anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been following along. I&amp;rsquo;ve started working on an FM transmitter with the grand ambition of eventually hosting some sort of radio show. Nothing fancy, mind you - keeping it sensible at 1 watt to stay well within the restrictions of the General User Radio License. The whole thing started as a bit of a thought experiment really, but now I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely excited about the possibilities. And definitely no music, because that way lies licensing madness and paperwork that would make my head spin. Radio podcasting, perhaps? Not sure that&amp;rsquo;s even a proper term, but it sounds about right for whatever this endeavour might become.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Physics, Panic, and Treetop Revelations</title><link>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/physics-panic-treetop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/physics-panic-treetop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another week gone by, and I&amp;rsquo;m sat here trying to work out what actually happened versus what feels like it happened. Spoiler alert: physics was involved in both versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week brought a school trip that served as a rather dramatic reminder of why I have such nice, safe indoor hobbies. Someone in their infinite wisdom decided it would be character-building to start us off on one of those treetop obstacle courses. I&amp;rsquo;m not exaggerating when I say it was the scariest thing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done. Picture this: me, twenty feet up in the canopy, quite literally shaking in my boots while white-knuckling safety lines and questioning every life choice that led to being suspended on wobbly planks between trees. Every few minutes I&amp;rsquo;d be reminded exactly why I prefer my feet firmly planted on solid ground, ideally indoors, preferably near a nice warm computer that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sway in the wind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello, World (Properly This Time)</title><link>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/a-proper-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/a-proper-hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>So here we are – my first &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; post on this little corner of the internet. I say proper because I already threw up that story I wrote, but this feels more like an actual introduction to whatever this blog is going to become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on automating the whole publishing process so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to make two separate remote connections to the server every time I want to push changes. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those small inefficiencies that drives you mad when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to maintain any kind of writing momentum. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be pushing updates manually a few times a week, usually around 12pm whenever I remember to do it. And with that schedule comes absolutely no promise of a new post each time – sometimes it&amp;rsquo;ll just be me tinkering with the backend or fixing typos I missed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This Is Where It Starts (Again)</title><link>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//zl2dtl.xyz/posts/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what this thing will turn into. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the fourth time I&amp;rsquo;ve done this. Different names, different sites, different looks. Probably because what I need from it keeps changing. Sometimes it was just for keeping track of project notes. Sometimes it was where I dumped thoughts that didn&amp;rsquo;t have anywhere else to go. Now it&amp;rsquo;s something else, I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s stuff rattling around in my head that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as a text message or a quick photo or something you&amp;rsquo;d bring up over coffee. Some of it&amp;rsquo;s quick, those ideas that disappear if you don&amp;rsquo;t grab them right away. Other stuff sticks around, going in circles until I finally write it down somewhere. That somewhere is here now.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>